Guide to the Cased Image File 1840-ongoing PR 12
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
- Series II: Daguerreotype, 2
  - David Reese Griffith [Allen, A.M. (Amos M.), 1823-1907], [ca1845-1870s] (Item 2-459)
    Sitter is father of donor.
  - Mrs. David Reese Griffith (Sara Jane Coleman) (Item 2-460)
    Female figure, seated, 3/4-length, front view, with right elbow on table, hair parted in middle, left hand on lap, wearing black dress, ring.
    Sitter is mother of donor.
  - James Gallagher Jr. (Item 2-461)
    3/4-length portrait of young boy, seated with hands on arms of chair, wearing white shirt, velvety pants, white socks, hair in shoulder-length curls.
  - James William Gowdey [Welling], 1853/00/00 (Item 2-462)
    3/4-length male figure, seated, front view, with right hand on table, left hand on lap, clean-shaven, kerchief in coat pocket.
    Sitter is "a son of the American Revolution" whose "great grandfather was with General George Washington at the Battle of Fort Lee" and is the father of the donor.
  - James William Gowdey (Item 2-463)
    Male figure, right elbow on table, clean-shaven, white shirt, plaid vest, black bow tie and jacket, long wavy hair to below ears.
  - Mrs. James Gallagher and James Gallagher Jr. (Item 2-464)
    Double portrait of mother holding infant child on her lap; adult wearing dark colored dress with brooch at throat, rings and open finger gloves; infant wearing white dress with hands on lap.
    James Jr. later because the husband of the donor and was a Representative Senator and chairman of the State Board of Charities of the State of Connecticut.
  - Unidentified Young Female Greenwood Family Member or Friend [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-465)
    Young girl, seated front view, full length, with left hand on table and right hand on lap, wearing necklace, yellow checked dress, bracelets and pink slippers with white stockings.
  - Isaac John Greenwood and Mary Greenwood (Item 2-466)
    Double portrait, male leaning over female; male wearing white collar and yellow foulard, female wearing large bonnet; male holding book?
  - Mary Louise Greenwood (1828?-1862) (Item 2-467)
    Female figure, standing, front view, hair parted in middle, wearing cape, white lace collar, left hand resting on table.
  - Mrs. Isaac John Greenwood II (Mary Agnes Rudd) (Item 2-468)
    3/4-length young girl, seated, front view, hands on lap, wearing striped dress.
  - George H. Morris (Item 2-469)
    Infant, full length, hair parted in middle, wearing plaid dress with short sleeves and white slip.
    Card catalogue states that sitter is grandson of George Hall; originally labeled as "#20".
  - Colonel George B. Hall, 1849/07/00 (Item 2-470)
    Male figure, head turned slightly to his right, goatee, in uniform of U.S. Army officer, cap on table, left hand in opening of coat.
    Card catalogue states that writing on inside of case read :"July-1849, 8 O'clock in the evening"; originally labeled as "#3".
  - Mary Ferry Hall [Knapp, William R.], [1840s-ca1851] (Item 2-471)
    Female figure, seated, wearing bonnet with sash under chin, flowers in bonnet, gloves, long gold chain.
    Original label in case identifies image as #19.
  - George Albert Halsey, before 1850/09/00 (Item 2-472)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, black bow tie, weskit with top button hole open.
    Accompanying note describes sitter's history, including that he was the son of Gordon Halsey and Eliza Osborn who was daughter of Capt. Jonathon Osborn; this Daguerreotype was given by sitter to his fiancée, Josephine Mead, before their marriage in 1850
  - Mrs. Abram Stevens Hewitt (Sarah Amelia Cooper) [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-473)
    Female figure, seated, wearing horizontally striped dress, lace shawl, left arm on table, brooch.
  - Mrs. Abram Stevens Hewitt (Sarah Amelia Cooper) (Item 2-474)
    Female figure, front view, long curls at sides of head, hair parted in middle, looking off to sitter's upper right.
  - Sarah Cooper Hewitt [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-475)
    Young girl, left arm behind her, wearing white dress, standing in front of landscape background.
  - Brother of George B. Dieter or Unidentified Hincken Family Member or Friend (Item 2-476)
    3/4-length portrait of male figure, seated with right arm on table, clean shaven, wearing chain in vest, white shirt, black bow tie.
    Card catalogue states that note originally found in case reads "Probably brother of George Dieter".
  - George B. Dieter (Item 2-477)
    Male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, high white collar, black bow tie, clean shaven.
    The obituary notice that accompanies this image was originally pinned to the velvet lining.
  - George Dieter Jr. ( ) [Williamson Brothers] (Item 2-478)
    Post-mortem portrait of infant, laying on white cover and head resting on large white pillow, wearing white off-the shoulder dress.
    Sitter is son of George Dieter and Julia (Malbone) Dieter.
  - Mrs. Edward Boyd Hincken (Helen Suydam Pyle) and Unidentified Young Female Hincken Family Member or Friend [Williamson, Charles H.], [ca1844-1885] (Item 2-479)
    Double portrait, female figure seated holding left hand on hand of young girl, girl is wearing purple dress, female wearing glove and bonnet with striped sash.
  - Jacob Lindley Pyle [Marshall & Porter] (Item 2-480)
    3/4-length portrait of seated male figure, left elbow on table, landscape backdrop, right arm on lap, wearing white shirt and black bow tie, clean-shaven.
  - Jacob Lindley Pyle (Item 2-481)
    Half-length portrait of young male figure, seated with left arm resting on table, wearing white shirt, black bow tie, large jacket.
  - Jane Malbone Dieter and Julia Malbone Pyle [Durang], 1849/00/00 (Item 2-482)
    Double portrait, adult female seated wearing brooch, young female standing with arm around adult and wearing vertically striped dress, necklace.
  - Mrs. Edward Boyd Hincken (Helen Suydam Pyle) (Item 2-483)
    Full-length portrait of young girl, seated with left hand on back of chair, feet on seat of chair, front view, hair parted in middle, wearing white off the shoulder dress and necklace.
  - Helen Suydam Pyle (Mrs. Edward Boyd Hincken) (Item 2-484)
    Infant wearing white gown, hands clasped on lap.
  - Unidentified Male Pyle Family Member (Item 2-485)
    Male figure, seated, front view, wearing white shirt and black bow tie, light colored hair.
  - Unidentified Female Hincken Family Member or Friend (Item 2-486)
    3/4-length portrait of female figure, front view, wearing high white collar, black dress, cross on collar of dress.
  - Unidentified Young Female Hincken Family Member or Friend (Item 2-487)
    3/4-length portrait of young girl wearing off the shoulder basket weave pattern dress, hair to just above neckline and parted in middle, right arm dropped to side, left arm held up to stomach.
  - Reverend John Cabaly Middleton and Mrs. John Cabaly Middleton (Item 2-488)
    Double portrait, male and female figures seated, male wearing patterned vest and neckerchief, clean-shaven, hand on right thigh, female wearing polka dot dress and holding book in left hand (Bible?).
    Reverend is from the Protestant Episcopal Church of Glen Cove, Long Island.
  - Eugene A. Hoffman (Item 2-489)
    Male figure, front view, right arm resting on table which holds two books, wearing white shirt, bow tie, ring, clean-shaven.
  - Eugene A. Hoffman (Item 2-490)
    Male figure, front view, left arm resting on table, wearing white shirt and Buster Brown collar, black bow tie, hair straight and long to above neck, right hand resting on lap.
  - Herman Laidlie Hoffman (Item 2-491)
    Male figure seated wearing high hat and bow tie, sideburns, hands clasped on lap, stuffed duck near right arm.
  - Unidentified Male Hurlbutt Family Member or Friend (Item 2-492)
    Male figure, bearded, front view, wearing striped neckerchief, dark vest, white shirt.
  - M. Duane Jones [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-493)
    Female figure, seated with left elbow resting on table and right hand on lap, wearing white collar dark shawl, earrings, rings, necklace, small bow at collar.
  - William Sullivan Ide and George Elmore Ide (Item 2-494)
    Two young boys, one seated wearing Buster Brown jacket and collar, right hand on lap, one standing wearing 3/4 length blouse with belt, both holding book together.
  - William Sullivan Ide and George Elmore Ide (Item 2-495)
    Two young boys, seated boy has hands on lap and is facing off to his left, wearing white collar, buttoned blouse, standing bow has right arm resting on left shoulder of seated bow, wearing long dark blouse with buttons down front.
  - John Romeyn Brodhead [Plumbe, John, Jr., 1809-1857;Brady's Gallery], 1846/10/01 (Item 2-496)
    Male figure wearing eyeglasses, white collar and shirt, dark coat, clean shaven, white muffler around neck.
  - Franics T. Lequier [Plumbe, John, Jr., 1809-1857] (Item 2-497)
    Male figure bald with hair on sides, wearing white shirt and high white collar, black bow tie, clean-shaven.
    Card catalog states that donor is grandchild of sitter.
  - Jane Averell Laidley [Root, S.; Root, M.A.] (Item 2-498)
    Young girl seated holding doll on lap, feet crossed, wearing off the shoulder dress and shiny black boots, hair parted in middle with curls.
    Sitter is Great, great, grand daughter of Samuel Blachley Webb, aide de camp of General George Washington.
  - Jenny Lind (Item 2-499)
    Female figure, seated with hair parted in middle, long sleeved dress, hands on lap.
    Card catalog states that mat is labeled "84 JLX"
  - Unidentified Female (Item 2-500)
    Female figure seated with left hand on lap, wearing black dress with white collar and buttons down front, white hairpiece.
  - E. Livingston or Unidentified Young Female Fisher Family Member or Unidentified Young Female Livingston Family Member or Friend [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-501)
    Young girl, seated with left elbow resting on table, right hand on lap, wearing red ribbon back of hair, white collar and cuffs, book on table.
    Sticker on case states that written on back of plate is "E. Livingston".
  - E. Livingston [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-502)
    Male figure, bearded, wearing high white collar and white shirt, vest with gold chain, bow tie.
    Sticker on case states that written on back of dag plate is name: E. Livingston, though this sitter is also identified there as either Eugene A. Livingston or a Fisher descendent.
  - E. Livingston or Unidentified Female Fisher Family Member or Unidentified Female Livingston Family Member or Friend [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-503)
    Female figure, seated with left hand on table, right hand on lap, wearing white collar and cuffs, hair parted in middle, light eyes, blemish or freckle on chin, brooch at neck.
  - Unidentified Young Female Livingston Family Member or Friend (Item 2-504)
    Young girl, seated, front view, full length, wearing necklace, off the shoulder knee-length dress with plaid bows at sleeves and high socks.
  - Unidentified Young Female Livingston Family Member or Friend (Item 2-505)
    Young girl, seated with left arm resting on side of chair, wearing patterned dress with plaid ribbons on sleeves and lace cuffs, hands on lap, hair parted in middle.
  - Unidentified Female Livingston Family Member or Friend [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-506)
    Female figure, seated, front view, wearing white collar and cuffs, left hand resting on table, brooch at collar, yellow chain on blouse.
  - Unidentified Male Livingston Family Member or Friend (Item 2-507)
    Male figure, seated, front view, side burns, high white collar, white shirt, black bow tie, gold chain in vest.
  - Lt. Fordham Morris in Uniform [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-508)
    Male figure, front view, in Civil War Union Army Officer's uniform, fourth button hole unbuttoned, clean shaven, wearing hat.
  - Marianna Magdalina Monachesi (Item 2-509)
    Female figure seated, 3/4-length, hair parted in middle, necklace, right hand on lap, glove on left hand, long earrings.
  - Mary A. Mann (Item 2-510)
    Young girl seated with left hand over right wrist, wearing checked dress, hair short to neck.
    Sitter is daughter of Levi and Mary (Stevens) Mann, and married Edwin Childs in 1868, and is mother of Lillian E. Childs.
  - Mary Stevens Mann or Unidentified Female Mann Family Member or Friend (Item 2-511)
    Female figure, seated, curls, necklace, brooch, right hand resting on lap, rings, white cuffs, off the shoulder dress.
    Accompanying note states that Mary Stevens Mann is wife of Levi Stevens and Mother of Mary A. Mann Childs.
  - Micah Mann (Item 2-512)
    Male figure, front view, seated, wearing white shirt and collar, bow tie, clean shaven, vest with large buttons, left hand resting on book on table, sitter is slightly off center.
    Sitter is son of Seth Mann and great grandfather of Lillian E. Childs.
  - David Miller and Mrs. David Miller (Jane Ann Schuyler) [Weston] (Item 2-513)
    Male and female figures seated, female wearing red checked bonnet and white collar, cuffs, male is bearded wearing white collar and shirt, chain on vest, left hand on lap.
  - Mrs. David Miller (Jane Ann Schuyler) and Schuyler Miller (Item 2-514)
    Female figure seated with infant on lap, holding male Colonial doll in her left hand, wearing print dress, infant wearing white dress.
    Mrs. David Miller is mother of Schuyler.
  - Crystal Palace, 1854/00/00 (Item 2-515)
    Interior View of South Nave of Crystal Palace in its second year of exhibition, with statues, windows, stairs and other structural elements of building.
    Original case for this image in Cased Images Collection: PR-012-6-7
  - Bache McEvers Whitlock (Item 2-516)
    Infant seated wearing white gown with red necklace, hands on lap.
  - Mrs. William Whitlock (Eliza Haight Scott) (Item 2-517)
    Female figure, 1/4 profile, wearing black v-neck dress with white blouse under, hair parted in middle, white lace head covering.
    Duplicate image.
  - Mrs. William Whitlock (Eliza Haight Scott) (Item 2-518)
  - 2 Unidentified Young Female Stagg Family Members and 1 Unidentified Male Stagg Family Member [Jones & Co.] (Item 2-519)
    Two young girls standing with young boy seated on highchair center, girls wearing plaid dresses and red necklaces, bow wearing purple blouse and blue embroidered skirt? with pants, shoes visible.
  - Catherine Stagg (Item 2-520)
    Female figure seated with right arm resting on book on table, wearing brooch and rings, hair in curls on sides of head.
  - Esther Stagg (post-mortem) (Item 2-521)
    Young girl laying on dark background, viewed from above, holding flowers in right hand, wearing necklace, off-the-shoulder patterned dress, wrist band, eyes and mouth open, hair parted just slightly off center.
    Sitter is daughter of Thomas and Catherine Stagg, twin sister of Mary Stagg; buried in Greenwood Cemetery vault.
  - Thomas Stagg (Item 2-522)
    Male figure wearing bow tie, black jacket and vest, white shirt and collar, hair light and long to bottom of neck.
  - Thomas Stagg Jr. (Item 2-523)
    Young boy standing with right arm resting on table, dark jacket with white collar and handkerchief in pocket, bow at neck, hair parted on side.
  - Unidentified Young Female Stagg Family Member or Friend (Item 2-524)
    Young girl seated holding purse, wearing large gold bracelets just below elbows, black rope necklace, large patterned dress, hair parted in middle.
  - Catherine Elizabeth White (Mrs. John Steward) or Unidentified Female Stuyvesant Family Member or Friend [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-525)
    Female figure seated wearing large white bonnet with flowers, ribbons and lace, white bonnet ties in bow at neck, white lace collar, light colored cape, with scalloped edges, hands folded on lap, gold ring.
    White married John Steward, father of Mrs. Augustus Van Horne Stuyvesant.
  - Abraham Van Nest (Item 2-526)
    Male figure, front view, seated, clean shaven, wearing white collar, dark coat and vest, right hand on table, left hand on lap.
  - Amelia E. Van Buskirk [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-527)
    Female figure, front view, half-length, wearing white lace bonnet, sash on either side, seated, left arm resting on table, right hand on lap, wearing white cuffs, plaid blouse.
    Sitter is wife of Edward Henry Cornell.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-528)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket, white shirt and neckerchief, white hair?, black vest, 1/4 length.
  - Unidentified Male (Item 2-529)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black coat, polka dot tie, white collar, arms crossed over chest, bearded, head tilted upward slightly, 1/4 length, curtain in background.
  - Unidentified Male (Post-mortem) [Phoenix] (Item 2-530)
    Male figure, profile view, wearing white collar and black jacket, laying on cloth, gray hair.
    Photographer is probably French.
  - Unidentified Male [Walker, S.L.] (Item 2-531)
    Male figure, front view, wearing black jacket with handkerchief in pocket, black bow tie, white shirt and collar (up), bearded, sideburns.
  - Unidentified Female and Infant [Whitehurst] (Item 2-532)
    Female figure seated holding infant on lap, female wearing black dress with white blouse, brooch, earrings, hair parted in middle and pulled back, infant wearing white dress with white socks and black shoes.
  - Unidentified Female [Whitehurst Gallery (Washington, D.C.)] (Item 2-533)
    Female figure, profile view, 3/4 length, seated wearing bonnet with white ties at neck, white lace collar, black dress, hands on lap, light colored cuffs.
  - Louisa Lennox (Whitney) Wright, 1850/00/00-ca1852/00/00 (Item 2-534)
    Female figure, front view, seated, right arm on table, two books on table, wearing brooch, white collar in bow, dark dress with short dark sleeves and longer white sleeves.
  - Alanson Warren and Mary E. Warren (Item 2-535)
    Young girl and young boy, front view, girl is taller, wearing black dress, holding right hand of boy who is wearing buttoned up blouse and white collar.
  - Mrs. David Williams (Asenath Everts) (Item 2-536)
    Female figure, front view, wearing white bonnet, white collar, seated, right elbow resting on table.
  - Mrs. William E. Wells [Jube, T.S.], [1850s-ca1858] (Item 2-537)
    Female figure, front view, seated with right arm on table, wearing white collar blue bow tie, brooch, print dress, black lace finger-less gloves, hair parted in middle.
  - Anna Brookes Waller [Anson, Rufus], ca1860/00/00 (Item 2-538)
    Female figure, front view, long curls, plaid dress, chain type necklace.
  - Mrs. Joseph Waller (Martha Brookes) [Anson, Rufus], 1855/00/00 (Item 2-539)
    Female figure, front view, hair parted in middle, white collar, black bow, brooch, black dress, hands on lap.
    Sitter is daughter of Joseph Brookes.
  - William G. Waller and James M. Waller, ca1845/00/00 (Item 2-540)
    Two male figures, bearded, wearing high white collars, black bow ties, white shirts, male on left wearing patterned vest and holding cane in left hand, male on right holding cane in right hand.
    Sitters are brothers.
  - John Ward Jr. [Root, S.] (Item 2-541)
    Male figure, head turned 3/4 to left, moustache, white shirt, very large bow tie with vertical stripes on ends and fringe.
    Similar image of same sitter in Cased Images File?
  - John Ward Jr. [Anson, Rufus], 1863/00/00 (Item 2-542)
    Male figure, front view, bearded, wearing hat, white shirt, black bow tie, chain on vest, black coat and vest.
  - John Ward Jr. [Bogardus, A. (Abraham), 1822-1908], 1863/00/00 (Item 2-543)
    Male figure, profile to right, bearded, balding to center of head, white shirt and black bow tie, dark coat.
  - John Ward Jr., mid-late 1850s (Item 2-544)
    Young male figure, head turned to his left 3/4, clean shaven, white shirt and collar, polka dot bow tie, dark coat.
  - John Ward Jr., early 1850s (?) (Item 2-545)
    Young boy, front view, seated with left hand on book placed on table, wearing white shirt and collar, dark blouse buttoned up front.
  - John Ward Jr. [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-546)
    Male figure, front view, bearded, wearing white shirt, striped bow tie, chain on vest, military cap.
  - John Ward Jr. [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-547)
    Male figure, front view, bearded, wearing white shirt, striped bow tie, chain on vest.
    Similar image of John Ward Jr. in Cased Images File.
  - John Ward Jr. [Anson, Rufus], 1860/00/00 (?) (Item 2-548)
    Male figure, front view, bust, clean shaven, wearing white shirt, polka dot bow tie, cross pin on left lapel of vest, light colored coat and vest.
  - John Ward Jr., 1850s (Item 2-549)
    Male figure, head turned 3/4 to left, clean shaven, wearing white shirt, bow tie, hair parted on side.
  - John Ward Jr. [Anson, Rufus], [1851-1867] (Item 2-550)
    Young boy, front view, seated, wearing white collar, blouse buttoned up front, left hand on lap, hair long and curly to shoulders.
  - Mrs. Henry Ward [Binsse & Co.], [1850s] (Item 2-551)
    Female figure, half length, front view, wearing white blouse with high white collar, brooch, arms crossed on lap, white sleeves on blouse.
  - Capt. John Ward Jr. and 3 Officers of the 12th Regiment N.Y.S.M. in their tent at Harper's Ferry, 1862/00/00 (Item 2-552)
    Four male figures seated at open end of tent, ten pole center, two men seated at right wearing caps, 2 men at left bareheaded, clothing and other objects handing inside tent.
    Copy tintype (or tintype taken at same time) is elsewhere in Cased Images File.
  - Prescott Hall Ward (Item 2-553)
    Young male figure, front view, wearing white shirt, high white collar, polka dot bow tie, clean shaven.
  - Unidentified Male Webb Family Member or Friend (Item 2-554)
    Male figure seated with right arm resting on table, wearing dark jacket and dark silk vest, white shirt and collar with polka dot kerchief at neck, book on table.
  - Maria Abernathy Burr, Euphemia Cooper Burr, Melanthore Burr, and Charles Abernathy Burr (Item 2-555)
    Four youngsters, two girls and two boys, smallest is sitting in front, hands on lap, girl and boy are seated on either side of boy in front, one girl is standing behind him, front view full length.
    Enclosed note identifies the children (left to right, back row first) as Maria Abernathy, Euphemia Cooper, Melanthore, and Charles.
  - Edward Henry Cornell (Item 2-556)
    Portrait of a male figure with a moustache, wearing white collar, dark foulard, and white shirt.
    Edward Henry Cornell, 2nd Army Corps, Army of the Potomac, 66th Regiment; 55th N.Y.
  - Unidentified Female Constant Family Member or Friend (Item 2-557)
    Baby girl seated on plaid blanket, wearing white off-the-shoulder dress.
  - Charles Tighe Henry (Item 2-558)
    Portrait of a young boy, seated, with hands clasped on lap and hair parted on side.
    Note from case states that sitter is eldest son of Thomas Soden Henry and Emily Aglae (Cox) Henry.
  - John William Vaché [Atkins] (Item 2-559)
    Portrait of male, 3/4-length, front view, with right elbow resting on table, clean-shaven with curly hair, wearing white shirt with collar up, and dark bow tie, vest and jacket.
    Card catalogue states that sitter was born in New York city and is the eldest son of Alexandrea Felix Vaché, M.D.
  - Maria Anne Vaché (Item 2-560)
    Portrait of female, 3/4-length, front view, wearing large lace bonnet with long sash under chin, seated, with right hand resting on lap.
    Sitter is eldest daughter of Jean Lazare Vaché and Marie Anne Thoret.
  - William Pilcher (Item 2-561)
    Portrait of male, 3/4-length, with right arm resting on table, wearing pocket chain, white shirt with collar up, dark tie, jacket and vest.
  - Anna Vaché, ca1854/00/00 (Item 2-562)